Really? He had an offer for an anime?
Animation Production Studio
Producer
Tanabe Futoshi
Public Company
アニメの話 来たの
話だけなら結構早く来るんだって
They usually start to make offers early on.
その人も「挨拶だけ」って言ってたし
He even said he went there just to meet us.
そうなんだ
I see.
亜豆には言うなよな 変に期待させたくないから
Don't tell Azuki anything, though.
I don't want to get her hopes up.
でも なるよね 「REVERSI」の人気すごいもん ね
But it will become one, right?
Reversi's really popular after all.
Right?
Yeah.
面白いものは描いてれば必ずなる そう思ってやってる
If you make something good, it'll
eventually get turned into an anime.
That's our philosophy.
そうだ 「REVERSI」なら いつか必ず
That's right.
One day, Reversi will definitely...
yu
me
Dreams, dreams, dreams, dreams
ka
na
e
ru
ta
bi
ko
wa
re
te
yu
ku
me
As soon as I reach my goals, it all falls through again
na
ze
so
re
de
mo
ma
ta
So why do I run...
bo
ku
wa
sa
ga
su
ha
shi
ri
tsu
zu
ke
ru
...and search in spite of that?
hi
sa
shi
bu
ri
ni
de
atta
We met after such a long time
"
fu
n
i
ki
ka
watta?"
"Has the mood changed for us?"
tsu
ki
hi
wa
na
ga
re
ta
da
rou
So much time has passed
"
a
no
ko
ro
no
ho
u
ga
ta
no
shi
so
u
"
"It seemed like more fun back then"
ta
ku
sa
n
na
ku
shi
ta
We've lost so much
so
n
na
ko
to
wa
ki
zu
i
te
ru
n
da
I already know that, though
sa
ke
bi
tsu
zu
ke
ro
mo
ga
ki
tsu
zu
ke
ro
Don't stop screaming, don't stop struggling
da
re
no
ta
me
ni
na
n
ka
mou
i
da
rou?
You've done enough for others
ma
da
tsu
ta
e
i
ko
to
ga
a
ru
ma
da
I still, still have something I haven't told you yet
yu
me
no
sa
ki
ni
wa
yu
me
shi
ka
na
i
Beyond each of my dreams lies yet another dream
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)出品 仅供交流学习之用 禁止用于商业用途
---诸神字幕组---
台本: 共由         翻译: 新人&poopy       繁化: 謙謙
校对：绫女       时间轴：Color
Hot Springs and Confirmation
見ろよ サイコー
Look at this, Saikou.
昨日来た加藤さんの友達 北見リリカ
It's the person from yesterday, Katou's friend.
Profile
Name
Kitami Ririka
Female
December 29, 1994
Akita prefecture
Kana
Sex
DOB
Birthplace
Kitami Ririka.
一応声優デビューしてる まだ生徒Aとかだけど
She's making her debut as a voice actress.
She's only had roles like "Student A," though.
マジ てか そんな事調べてたのか
Really?!
Wait, you actually looked that up?
いや 「REVERSI」をアニメにしたいって会社があるって知ったら
Well, I just couldn't calm down when I realized there was a company willing to make an anime of Reversi.
なんか落ち着かなくなってきて
今からそんなんでどうすんだよ
You can't get so worked up over something this small.
アニメになるって決まったわけでもないし
It's not like we've gotten an actual anime.
And if we do manage to get one, it'll be far in the future.
なるとしても当分先
今は作品を面白くする事
The only thing to do now is to
concentrate on making our manga good.
サイコー 今度の正月休み 初めて少しは休めそうじゃん
Saikou.
Looks like this is the first time you can afford to take a break over New Year's.
Yeah.
30日くらいから3日までは休むつもり
I won't work from about the 30th until the 3rd.
って言っても やる事ないから 結局仕事してそうだけどな
That said, I'll probably end up working
anyways since I'll have nothing else to do.
旅行行かね
Wanna go on a vacation?
Huh?
香耶ちゃんと新婚旅行以来の旅行計画してんだけど
Kaya and I are planning for our first vacation since our honeymoon.
以来って あの時鬼怒川に2泊3日行ったきりかよ
Since your honeymoon?  When you went to Kinugawa for three days and two nights?
香耶ちゃんかわいそすぎだろ
I feel bad for Kaya.
その鬼怒川の同じ宿に4年半ぶりに行ってみるかなって
It's been four and a half years since we went to that inn in Kinugawa, so we wanted to visit it again.
香耶ちゃんがサイコーも誘おうって
Kaya wants to invite you this time.
な 何でだよ 2人で行けよ
Wh-Why?! The two of you should go.
俺 邪魔じゃん
I'd just be in the way.
そんなんじゃないって
No, you wouldn't.
何て言うか
Since we're always working together, it'd feel weird not to have you around for that sort of thing.
いつも仕事で一緒にいるから
逆にこういう時にサイコーがいないのは変な気がするって
俺も分かるんだ それ
I know how you feel.
社員旅行みたいな感じでさ 行かね
Just think of it as a company trip.
Won't you come?
Ah, this is like heaven on Earth.
極楽 極楽
じじくせーけど それしか言葉ないな
You sound like an old geezer, but I
can't think of anything more fitting.
ほんとに邪魔じゃなかったのかよ
You don't mind me being here, right?
何度も聞くなって 3人の方が楽しいじゃん
Stop asking that.
It's more fun with the three of us.
ならいいけど
Well, that's good then.
やっぱりこうやってのんびりするのは最高だよな
Kicking back like this really is great.
いつも必死に頑張ってるからこそ格別なんだって
It's only great because we work so hard.
Yeah. If I always came here, I wouldn't appreciate it as much.
しょっちゅう来れたら ありがたみないもんな
さあ 次はメシだ
Come on, time for food!
おおっ すげ～料理
Wow, this looks amazing!
遅いから 先にお酒だけ頂いてま～す
You guys are late, so I started drinking already!
てか 香耶ちゃん悪酔いしてない
Are you drunk, Kaya?
ささっ 秋人さん 今年もお世話になりましたー
Here you go. Akito, thanks for treating me well this year.
Y-Yeah.
真城もいつもありがとう 秋人さんがお世話になってます
Mashiro, thank you as well. You always look out for Akito.
ありがとう
Thanks, but I don't really drink—
でも 俺お酒あんまり飲め
Huh? What was that?
何
飲みます 飲みます
I'm drinking, I'm drinking.
食った 食った
I'm so full.
もう入んねぇ
Can't eat another bite...
さあ 恒例の卓球大会 開催
Now, it's time to begin the traditional ping pong competition!
てか こんな食べたあとすぐ
Wait, right after eating?
Huh? What was that?
何
やります やります
We'll do it, we'll do it!
危な
Watch out—
香耶ちゃん 強すぎだって
Kaya, you hit it too hard!
よぇーなぁ 男2人して
For a couple of guys, you two sure are weak!
じゃあ あたし左でやったげる
I'll switch to my left hand just for you.
くっそー なめやがって
Don't underestimate me, dammit!
動いたら 酒が回って
When I move around, everything spins...
もう無理
I'm done for.
真城 寝るんじゃないわい
Mashiro, don't fall asleep.
And another year ends well.
一緒に初日の出 見るんだから
We're going to watch the first sunrise of the new year.
おっ カウントダウン 始まるぞ
Now, towards the new year!
The countdown's about to start!
Ten, nine...
Eight, seven...
Six, five...
Four, three...
Two, one...
おめでとー 今年も頑張ろうぜ
Happy New Year!
Let's do our best this year, too!
Yeah!
「REVERSI」ならいける
Reversi can do... it...
何
What're you doing?
亜豆におめでとメール
Sending Azuki a "Happy New Year" text.
Another short text?
またひと言だろ
美保もね
Miho does it, too.
あなたたちはそうじゃないと変
It'd be strange if you two did anything else.
Oh, it's getting brighter.
明るくなってきた
今年もいい年でありますように
I wish for another good year.
「REVERSI」がもっともっと大ヒット
Let's turn Reversi into an even bigger hit.
真城は何もお願いしないの
Mashiro, aren't you going to wish for anything?
Huh? Are you supposed to wish for something on the first sunrise of the new year?
初日の出って願い事するんだっけ 初詣じゃなくて
Isn't that supposed to be on your first visit to a shrine?
普通 するから
That's what we normally do.
そっか じゃ 俺は
I see. Then, I wish...
香耶ちゃんとシュージンとこうしてずっと仲良くいられますように
...that I'll always be close to Kaya and Shuujin, just like this.
真城君 美保の恋人じゃなかったら
Mashiro! If you weren't Miho's
boyfriend, I'd have you for myself!
あたし 真城君でも
Hey!
やっぱり真城が来てくれてよかった
I'm really glad that you came along, Mashiro.
って 何で泣いてんだよ
Hey, why are you crying?
だって
Because it's good to be like this.
こういうのっていいじゃん
なんかうれしいじゃん
It makes me happy.
すごく幸せじゃん
Don't you feel happy, too?
だな
Yeah.
シュージン 香耶ちゃん ありがとな
Shuujin, Kaya. Thanks.
こんな楽しい正月初めてかも
This is probably the most fun New Year's I've ever had.
また来ようね
Let's come here again.
今度は美保も一緒に
Next time, Miho will be with us.
サイコー 起きてる
Saikou, are you still awake?
Yeah.
香耶ちゃんは
Kaya?
She fell asleep already.
寝ちゃったよ
俺は目がさえちゃって
I'm still wide awake, though.
俺も寝ようとしてたとこだけど
I was just about to go to sleep myself.
じゃ 俺もこっちで寝ようかな
Maybe I should sleep here, then.
気持ち悪ーだろ
That's gross.
中3の夏休みには同じ屋根の下で毎日寝てたじゃん
During summer break of our third year in middle
school, we slept under the same roof every night.
中3の夏休みか 懐かしいようなつい最近だった気もするけど
Summer break in middle school...
It feels nostalgic, but also like it was just yesterday.
あれから今まで休まず来たって言っていいよな 9年半
You could say we've been working nonstop ever since then.
Nine and a half years.
あっという間だな
It went by so fast.
Yeah.
きつい事もあったけど楽しかった
There were hard times, but it was fun.
俺たち「運」も持ってるんだよな
We've been lucky.
「うぬぼれ」「努力」「運」の運な
The "Luck" from "Conceit, Hard Work, Luck."
シュージンに出会えたのが俺の一番の運だと思う
I think meeting you was the luckiest thing that has ever happened to me.
「マンガ描こう」って言われてなかったら 今頃何してたか
If you hadn't asked me to make manga with you, I don't know what I'd be doing now.
他に何か目標見つけてたんじゃね
You would have found some other goal to work towards.
「日本一のマンガ家になる」「亜豆と結婚する」なんて大それた夢は持ってなかった
I didn't have any of these outrageous dreams before—
like becoming the number one manga
artist in Japan, or marrying Azuki Miho.
その夢もすぐそこまで 手の届くところまで来てる
Those dreams are right at my fingertips now.
「REVERSI」ならそれができる
Reversi can do it.
キザな事言っていい
Mind if I say something pretentious?
「旅の恥はかき捨て」どんなくさい事でも言えよ
Sure, say any snobby thing like "A man who's away from home need feel no shame."
俺はマンガも人生も同じだと思ってる
I think manga and life are the same thing.
週刊マンガなら1週間 人生なら死ぬまで
A weekly manga lasts for a week, and a life lasts until you die.
与えられた時間の中で どこまでいいものにできるか
It's making the best of whatever time you're given.
だから 手を抜いちゃいけないんだ
So, you can't hold back.
「うぬぼれ」や「運」も大事だけど 一番大切なのは
"Conceit" and "Luck" are important, but the most important one is
「努力」
"Hard Work."
全然キザじゃないじゃん 言うとおりだと思う
That wasn't pretentious at all.
I think you're spot on.
そして「体力」「精神力」最後は「根性」だろ
Don't forget "Strength of body,"
"Strength of mind," and lastly, "Guts"!
Right?
Yeah.
頑張ろうぜ
Let's do our best!
帰ったら仕事だな
When we get back, it's back to work!
すごいやる気だな
You two could have taken some more time off, but you're really eager to get back to work.
まだ休めるのにこんなに早く仕上げるとは
I wasn't expecting you to finish this quickly.
余裕を持って より良い原稿をと思ってますから
Since we had free time, we thought
we'd make the manuscript even better.
4日発売の2巻 もう重版かかった
We've already had a reprint of your second volume, which went on sale on the 4th.
1巻も累計で50万部だ
If you add in the total from your first volume, that makes 500,000 copies already.
やった
All right!
But, Zombie Gun...
でも「ZOMBIE☆GUN」も
いや 2巻はまだだ
No, its second volume isn't on sale yet.
今は「REVERSI」の方が伸びている
Right now, Reversi is selling more.
このまま順調なら追いつくかもしれないな
If it keeps going like this, you may catch up!
よしっ このまま突っ走っていこうぜ
Yeah! Full speed ahead!
Yeah!
どちらも人気は申し分ないが まだ半年だからなぁ
Both of them are plenty popular, but it's only been six months.
しかし この夏で「CROW」のアニメは終わる
However, the CROW anime will end this summer.
現状を考えれば やはりこの2つのどちらかしかないだろう
In our present situation, it has to be one of these two.
Super popular!
Title page in color!
Niizuma Eiji
A sudden
confrontation
that could
destroy
humanity!
視聴者の事を考えると 同じ作者の「ZOMBIE☆GUN」というのが一番いい流れかと
Choosing another work by the same author
would be the best way to transition the viewers.
Niizuma
Eiji
でも「ZOMBIE☆GUN」の展開では アニメがすぐ原作に追いついてしまう
Niizuma
Eiji
However, at the current rate Zombie Gun's plot is progressing, its anime would catch up quickly.
Ashirogi Mutou
その点「REVERSI」は1回の内容が濃いので追いつかれにくいかと
But Reversi would be harder to catch up with since each of its chapters is very dense.
Ashirogi Mutou
その内容が子供には難しすぎる 幅広く狙うならこっちだろ
Dense with content that kids can't understand!
If we want a wide audience, then it has to be Zombie!
そ それは制作者側に配慮してもらえば
Th-That's something the production staff will take into consideration.
何だ
What? Aida, you sound like you're really pushing for Reversi.
相田 やけに「REVERSI」推すな
雄二郎もまだやりたくないと言ってます なら「REVERSI」でしょう
Yuujirou said that he doesn't want to do an anime right now.
So, it has to be Reversi.
服部は何か言ってるか
Has Hattori said anything?
いえ アニメの話が来てるのは知ってますが
No.
He knows there's been some offers for an anime,
当分先の話だと思ってるでしょうから
but he thinks it won't happen for a long time.
なら 服部にも聞いておけ
Then, ask Hattori what he thinks about this.
OKなら「REVERSI」で決まりですか
If he says okay, is Reversi definitely getting an anime?
そうじゃない 秋からでもやる気があるかどうか
No.
We have to ask him first if he wants the fall slot.
まずはそこから聞かなければ話にならないと言ってるんだ
There's no point in discussing this until we've heard his answer.
雄二郎にももう一度聞いておけよ
And ask Yuujirou one more time.
「REVERSI」のアニメ化ですか
An anime adaptation of Reversi?
まだ 決定じゃないぞ
Nothing's certain yet.
編集長が秋からでもやる気があるか聞いておけと
The Chief Editor wants to know if you'd want it to start this fall.
「CROW」のあとですね なるほど
After CROW, then.
I see.
やる方向でいいな
So, you're saying yes, then?
ちょっと待って下さい
Give me a moment, please.
少し考えさせてもらえますか
I need to think about this.
何でだ 何も問題ないだろ
Why? There shouldn't be any problems with this.
いえ 「CROW」のアニメって 結局何年やりましたっけ
Well... How many years did the
CROW anime end up running for?
Um... A little under seven.
7年弱だな
長く続けるよりも 作品として納得のいくものにしたいんです
We'd rather have a work that we're satisfied with instead of one that has a long run!
亜城木君の言い方だと
At worst, going by what Ashirogi said, the
series could finish before the anime even starts.
下手をすればアニメが始まる前に連載が終了してしまう事も
何とかしてアニメをやってる間だけでも連載を続けるようにもっていけば
If they could just keep the series going while the anime is on air...
しかし 亜城木君は頑固だからな
They're pretty stubborn, though.
納得する形でなければ続けないだろう
They won't agree to keep it going unless they're completely satisfied with it.
What's going on? You look awfully serious.
どうした 深刻な顔して
いえ うれしいんですが 簡単に返事できる事では
Well, I'm happy about this, but I
can't give you an answer that easily.
だから何でだよ
But why?
普通「アニメ化」「やった」の2つ返事だろ
Normally you'd say either "An anime?!" or "All right!", and that'd be it.
と とにかく 少し考えさせて下さい
A-Anyways, just let me think about this first!
わ 分かった なるべく早くな
O-Okay, fine.
Make it quick.
Niizuma
で まあ 意思確認なんだけど
So, I'm just confirming this with you,
「ZOMBIE☆GUN」はまだアニメ化しない方向で
but right now, Zombie Gun shouldn't be made into an anime yet, right?
まだ早いんですよね
It's too early.
Yeah.
アニメの出来を良くするためにもできるだけ先の方がいい
The further ahead we are, the easier it will be to adapt this into an anime.
僕としては3年以上描いてからだと思ってる
I think you need to continue for at least three more years before we consider it.
ラジャーです
Roger.
で「CROW」のあとに始まるアニメは多分「REVERSI」になりそうだ
So, the anime that'll start after
CROW ends will probably be Reversi.
「REVERSI」ですか
Reversi?!
亜城木君に言えば アニメにしたいと言うに決まってる
If I tell Ashirogi, they'll definitely want to do the anime.
マンガを描き始めた時からの夢だと
It's been their dream ever since they started to draw manga.
なら その条件として「アニメをやってる間は連載を続けてくれ」と言えば
How about I tell them that in order to have an anime, they
have to keep the series going for the duration of the anime?
しかし それでマンガが面白くなくなったら
However, if that causes the manga to get boring...
連載がアニメ開始前に終わる可能性を上に正直に報告しておく
Maybe I should be honest and tell the higher-ups that the manga might end before the anime even begins.
いや それではアニメ化自体なくなるかも
But if I do that, we might lose the offer.
深く考えず黙ってアニメにしてもらえばいいだけか
In the end, maybe it's best to simply
keep quiet and just agree to the anime.
But that's just being irresponsible.
それではいくら何でも無責任では
駄目だ 1人で考えて決める事ではないな
It's no use! This isn't something I can decide by myself.
いいか 焦るな 焦るなよ
Listen, don't freak out.
Don't freak, okay.
落ち着いて聞いてくれ
Keep calm and listen.
はい
Okay.
まだ 決定という話ではないが
This isn't definite yet,
「REVERSI」を秋からアニメでやる気があるか上が聞いてきた
but the higher-ups are asking me if we'd like to have an anime for Reversi in the fall.
ア アニメ
A-Anime?
うわぁ
Yes!
やったぁ
サイコー
Saikou!
シュージン
Shuujin!
ついに
Finally!
いや 待て だから決定ではない
No, wait!
It's not a sure thing!
秋からやる気があるかどうか聞かれただけだ
They just wanted to know whether you'd want to do it this fall or not!
あるに決まってるじゃないですか
Of course we'd want that!
ないわけないじゃないですか
There's no way we wouldn't!
僕たちがOK出せば 決まりって事ですよね
If we agree, then it's all settled, right?
やります 絶対に
We'll do it! For sure!
いや 本当にまだそこまでの話じゃないんだ
No, it isn't really decided yet.
Aww yeah!
Anime! Anime! Anime! Anime!
アニメ アニメ
とにかく落ち着いてくれ
Just calm down!
Ashirogi Mutou
アニメが終わるまで連載を続ける
Continue the series until the anime ends?
Yeah.
もちろん 黒悪魔と白悪魔
I mean that when the confrontation between the white and black demons, Weiss and Schwarz, concludes,
シュバルツとヴァイセの対決が終わっても
the three of us would sit down and figure out what happens next.
3人で考えてやっていこうって意味だ
アニメやってる間は終わらせてはいけないって条件が出されたって事ですか
Were you given the condition that the series can't end while the anime is running?
いや 上はそこまで言ってきてないが
No, they haven't gotten into that kind of detail yet.
アニメ制作会社の立場を考えたら
But when you consider the anime production company's position,
できれば長くやってほしいだろう
they'd want it to last as long as possible.
秋からのアニメ
An anime starting in the fall...
今の構想だと その秋にはシュバルツとヴァイセの決着はつきます
At our pace, by that time the confrontation between Schwarz and Weiss will be over.
絶対にアニメ放送中に連載が終わっては駄目なんですか
Do we have to keep the series going for as long as the anime is running?
いや だから絶対ではない
Like I said, that's not set in stone.
しかし もしアニメが始まる頃に連載が終わる予定だと上に話せば
However, if I tell the higher-ups that you're planning to end the series right around when the anime starts,
この話はなくなるかもしれない
this offer may be pulled off the table.
その事を言わずにアニメ化したいと言うのも後ろめたい気がするんだ
And I would feel guilty if I gave them the go-ahead for the anime without telling them about this.
ならば アニメ終了まで
So, if you could continue it until the anime ends...
いや せめてアニメが始まって1年ぐらいは連載を続けると
No, if you could just tell me you'll keep it going a year into the anime, I'd feel a lot better.
君たちに言ってもらえれば 僕としてもやりやすいという事だ
サイコー ここでアニメにしない手はないよな
Saikou, there's no way we can say no.
アニメ開始から1年は原作を終わらせない
We won't end our manga until a year into the anime.
それでいいですね
That's good enough, right?
それで作品の質は絶対に落ちないか
Can you guarantee that the quality of the manga won't drop at all?
「REVERSI」は文句なしの傑作だ
Reversi is a masterpiece!
引き延ばして 作品の質だけは落としたくない
I don't want to lower its quality by prolonging it!
この前 そう決めたばかりだろ
Didn't we just decide not to do that?!
でも アニメにしてもらいたいだろ
But you want it made into an anime, right?!
当たり前だ
Of course I do!
服部さん
Hattori.
秋までなら連載も1年続く事になります
By this fall, the manga will have been running for a year.
アニメもその分原作のストックができる
That's a year's worth of story
material for the anime to work with.
それじゃ駄目なんですか
Isn't that enough?
ならば 一度アニメの話は見送り連載を完結させて
By that logic, it'd be best to pass up this
opportunity and wait until you end the series,
and if an offer comes for an anime after that, we should take it then.
それでも アニメ化したいという話があったらしてもらうという考え方もある
それは駄目です
We can't do that!
せっかく話が来てるのに見送るなんて
We've finally got an offer, so we can't pass it up!
このチャンスを逃すなんてありえない
There's no way we can miss this chance!
サイコー いいよ
Saikou, it's fine.
俺が頑張って原作を書けばいいんだ 何とかしてみせる
I just have to work really hard on the story.
I'll make it work, somehow.
シュージン
Shuujin.
それは無理に続けて質が落ちてもという事か
You mean you'll intentionally drag it out, even if the quality suffers?
いえ 落とさずにやってみせます
No! I'll see to it that the quality doesn't drop!
どうしたんだ 君たちらしくないな
What's going on? This isn't like you two.
いや 連載を続けてほしいと僕が言いだしたんだが やっぱりこれは変だ
Well, I was the one who wanted you to
continue the manga, but this is just strange.
アニメにはしたい しかし そのために作品の質が変わる事は絶対にしない
I was expecting you to say:
"We want an anime, but not if it means dropping the quality of our work."
君たちなら そう言い張ると思っていた
違うんです
That's not it.
高木は僕のために 僕個人の夢のために
Takagi's doing this for me.
For my personal dream.
ちょっ サイコー
Hey, Saikou...
中学の時 マンガを描き始める前
Back in middle school,
before I started to draw manga,
今 声優をしている亜豆美保と約束したんです
I made a promise to Azuki Miho, the voice actress.
僕たちの作品がアニメになり そのヒロインを彼女がやる
That our manga would become an anime, and that she would play the lead female role in it.
その夢がかなったら結婚する
And that once that dream came true, we'd get married.
夢がかなうまではよそ見をせず デートもなし会う事もしない
Since then, neither of us has strayed from that path. We haven't gone on dates, or even seen each other.
バカげてると思うでしょうけど 本当なんです
I know it sounds ridiculous, but it's the truth.
高木が僕と一緒にマンガ家になろうと誘ってくれて
Takagi asked me back then if I wanted to become a manga author with him.
その時偶然その夢も生まれ
And at the same time, coincidentally, this dream was born.
だから僕は一緒にやる決心をしたんです
That's why I resolved to do it together with him.
高木はその夢をかなえさせようと
Takagi is trying to fulfill that dream for me.
それがあれだけアニメ化にこだわってた理由か
So that's the reason you are so
obsessed with getting an anime?
なので その個人の夢のために
I don't want our manga to get boring just for the sake of getting an anime and fulfilling my personal dream.
作品をつまらなくしてまでアニメにするのは反対です
服部さんが言ったように
Just like you said, if an anime offer comes after we're done with our series, we can take it then.
連載が完結してからそれでもアニメの話があればでいい
何 言ってんだよ つまらなくなんてしない
What are you talking about?!
It won't get boring!
今 話が来たんだ 今 受ければいい
We have an offer now! We should accept it now!
どんな事をしてもだ
No matter what!
"No matter what"?! Even if the
quality of our manga goes down?
どんな事をしても作品の質が落ちてもか
亜豆だって そんな事望むはずない
Azuki wouldn't want that either!
服部さん
H-Hattori?
いやぁ ごめん
Ah, I'm sorry. It looks like I was wrong.
僕が間違っていたようだ
話が来てるんだ 素直にやりたいと言えばいい
We have an offer. I should just honestly say I want to do it.
Because Ashirogi Mutou wants to do it.
亜城木夢叶はやりたがってるんだからな
いいよ 連載もやりたいようにやろう
It's fine.
Just do your series the way you want to.
いつ終わっても構わない
I don't care when it ends.
何か文句言われたら 僕が責任を取る
If they complain, I'll accept responsibility for it.
服部さん
Hattori...
何で急に
Why did you suddenly...
いい夢じゃないか
It's a nice dream.
君たちの作品がアニメになり ヒロインを亜豆美保がやる
To have your work become an anime, and to have Azuki Miho play the heroine in it.
それがかなったら結婚
If that happens, then you get married.
中学の時から持ち続けてたというのもすばらしい
And it's wonderful that you've had that dream since middle school.
その夢をかなえるためにもアニメにしよう 僕は応援する
In order to fulfill it, let's do this anime.
I'll support you!
服部さん
Hattori...
僕は大人になりすぎた そういう純粋な気持ちを失ってたのかもしれない
I've become too much of an adult.
I may have lost that innocent way of thinking.
「アニメにしたいか」と聞かれたんだ
They asked if I wanted an anime.
「したい」「どうしてもしたい」と答えればいい
I should have replied, "Yes! I want it so badly!"
Ashirogi Mutou
それだけでいいんだ うん
That's all there is to it. Yeah.
Ashirogi Mutou
ねえ さっきまで服部さん来てたんだよね
Hey, Hattori came by here earlier, right?
うん 来てた
Yeah, he did.
で 何で2人ともそんなに締まりがないの
So, why do you guys look so relaxed?
Oh?
そう
Do we?
香耶ちゃんが来てくれてるからかな
Maybe it's because you're here!
うん 香耶ちゃんかわいいから
Yeah! Because you're so cute!
うん かわいい
Cute!
超かわいい
Super cute!
あ あんたたち 一体
Who are you people?
そうか 亜城木君たちも乗り気か
I see. So Ashirogi are hyped up for it.
はい 是非「REVERSI」アニメ化で進めて下さい
Yes! So please go ahead with Reversi's anime adaptation!
Storyboards for
Anime
雄二郎
Storyboards for
Anime
Yuujirou!
何だ これ
What's this?
新妻君がアニメ用に描いた「ZOMBIE☆GUN」のオリジナルネーム
Niizuma wrote these for the anime.
Original storyboards for Zombie Gun.
20話分です
20 of them!
ア アニメ用 オリジナルネーム
Original storyboards for an anime?!
だって お前アニメ化はまだ早いって言ってたじゃないか
But you said it was too early for an adaptation!
I thought so too, but...
僕はそう思ってたんですけど
「REVERSI」ですか
Reversi?!
ああ 亜城木君ファンでもある新妻君としてはうれしいだろ
Yeah. As an Ashirogi fan, you must be happy for them, right?
うれしいですけど
I'm happy, but if their volume sales
surpass mine, then I won't be anymore.
コミックスの売り上げを超されたらうれしくないかもです
う～ん 確かに
Well, yes.
アニメ化されたら逆転って事も
If they get an anime, they might make a comeback in their sales.
だからといって 「REVERSI」のアニメ化を止めるなんて事は
Even so, there's no way we can stop a Reversi anime from happening.
「ZOMBIE☆GUN」をやるって言ったら どうなるんです
If I said I wanted an anime of
Zombie Gun, what would happen then?
だから すぐに原作に追いつくから それはできないと何度も言ってるだろ
But I've said over and over that it's too early for that! The anime would catch up way too quickly!
だったら アニメ用オリジナル話をいっぱい作ればいいと思いますけど
Then all I have to do is create a bunch of original stories for the anime!
「ZOMBIE☆GUN」をまだアニメ化しないと言っていたのは
I had simply assumed that we should turn the anime
down because it would catch up to the manga.
原作に追いつくという僕の勝手な考えからです
でも 新妻君ならこうしてアニメ用のネームをどんどん描ける
But I didn't account for Niizuma's abilities. He can keep churning out these original storyboards for the anime!
面白いですね アニメを意識して映像に映えるように出来てる
These are good. He's made them with an anime in mind—frames that will look good on TV.
Yeah. He really is a genius.
ほんとに天才だな
「ZOMBIE☆GUN」やりますよ真の一番の作品にするためにも
We're gonna do Zombie Gun! I'll
make it the true number one series!
亜城木君にも秋からやる方向でと
I already told Ashirogi that it was likely we'd do their series as a fall anime.
話しちゃったのか
You told them already?!
はい
Yes.
Oh, crap.
まいったな
作家にまで聞けとは言ってないぞ
I never told you to ask the authors.
すみません
Sorry.
が 俺も「ZOMBIE☆GUN」はやらないという返事だと思っていた
However, I also expected that you
would say we shouldn't do Zombie Gun.
もっと慎重に確認を取るべきだったな すまない
I should have been more careful in asking.
Sorry.
弱りましたよ 新妻君も亜城木君もやる気満々で
They've already been informed, and both
Niizuma and Ashirogi are excited about it.
どちらも秋がいいのか
Are they both okay with this fall?
「ZOMBIE☆GUN」「REVERSI」
No matter which one we choose, both Zombie Gun and Reversi will eventually get an anime anyway.
今回見送ってもいつかアニメになる作品だ
「REVERSI」は今でなければ駄目です
Reversi has to be done now!
それはこっちも同じ
Same goes for Zombie Gun!
今「REVERSI」をやられたら アンケートでもコミックスでも
If you do Reversi now,
we might be overtaken in both
volume sales and survey rankings.
超されるかもしれませんからね
これはどっちが真の看板になるかの
This will decide which series...
分かれ目です
is the true flagship!
真の看板か
The true flagship...
どちらをやるかは今日中に俺が決める
I'll have my decision by the end of the day.
だ だから 決定ではないと何度も言っただろう
Th-That's why I told you nothing was decided yet!
新妻さんがアニメ用にネーム描いてるんじゃ
If Niizuma is drawing storyboards for the
anime, then Zombie Gun has a stronger case.
「ZOMBIE☆GUN」の方が強いですよね
「CROW」の後番だし そうなる可能性は高いだろうな
It would follow up CROW, and it
does seem like a more likely choice.
決めるのは編集長だが
The Chief Editor will decide, but you
probably shouldn't get your hopes up.
こういうのはあまり期待しない方がいいのかもしれない
Mashiro
ねえ 昨日服部さん来たのよねぇ
Hattori came yesterday, right?
ああ 来たな
Yeah.
で何で2人ともそんな覇気のない顔してんの
So, why do you two look so unmotivated?
Oh?
そう
We do?
おかしいな 香耶ちゃんが来てくれてるのに
That's strange.
Even though you're here...
そうだな 超かわいい香耶ちゃんが来てるのに
Yeah. Even though the super cute Kaya is here...
あんたたち どうしたのよ
What is with you two?
Oh, Hattori, come on in—
服部さんいらっしゃい
失礼する
Excuse me.
え ああ はい
Uh, sure.
お疲れさまです
Hello.
こういう事は直接言った方がいいと思って
I thought I should tell you news like this in person.
こういう事って
"News like this"?
アニメ化の話だが
It's about the anime adaptation...
do
u
shi
te
da
ro...
i
tsu
mo
so
u
sa
Why, I wonder?
chi
ka
zu
ku
ta
bi
ka
ra
ma
wa
ri
no
yu
me
Whenever I am close to fulfilling my goals, all effort becomes fruitless
ma
e
wo
mu
i
te
shi
ga
mi
tsu
i
te
sou
su
ko
shi
zu
tsu
We walk ahead, hold each other, and with little things
ya
ku
so
no
a
ba
sho
he
to
sa
e
ai
na
ga
ra
we support each other to reach what we promised
ji
shi
n
ga
ta
ri
na
i
to
ki
wa
mu
ne
ni
te
wo
a
te
When we lack confidence, we put a hand to our heart
bo
ku
ra
ga
tsu
zu
t
ta
pe
e
ji
yo
mi
ka
e
so
u
and reread the pages we assembled into a story
kyo
u
ma
de
so
shi
te
a
su
he
to
tsu
zu
i
te
yu
ku
no
sa
They lead up to today and continue into the morrow
ta
i
se
tsu
na
yu
me
ga
ka
na
u
so
no
hi
ma
de
We will always be ourselves
a
ri
no
ma
bo
ku
ra
de
zu
tto...
until the day that our dreams come true
Next Time
Preview
次は美保のターンだね
New mail
Now it's Miho's turn!
いや まだアニメ化が決まったわけじゃ
Well, we still don't know if we're getting an anime or not.
頑張れ 美保ー
Go for it, Miho!
ああ いや だから
Well, uh...
次回 訂正と宣言
Next time:
Correction and Declaration.
Correction and
Declaration
夢の前に厳しい現実が立ちはだかる
Cruel reality stands in the way of dreams!